(
"ai_sub_version": "1.11.0",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 3,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
アイドル革命進行中！
～今日の主役は夢の途中～
Idol Revolution in Progress!
~Today's Protagonist is in the Middle of a Dream~
世界一可愛い私
The cutest me in the world
宇宙一可愛い私
The cutest me in the universe
もっともっと聞かせてご褒美は...
Tell me more and more, and for your reward...
目を閉じて
Close your eyes
ちゅっ
*Kiss*
見つけてくれてサンキュー
Thank you for finding me
愛してくれてサンキュー
Thank you for loving me
生きがいにしちゃってもいいのよ
It's okay to make me your reason for living
一人じゃ無理 逆境
I can't handle adversity alone
みんながいれば最強
With everyone here, I'm the strongest
見つめ合ってよ思いっきり
Gaze at me with all your heart
好きになっちゃえ
Go ahead and fall in love!
涙じゃ何も解決しない
Tears won't solve anything
わかってるから
Because I know that
言葉で
With words,
態度で見せるわ
and with my actions, I'll show you.
覚悟はいい？
Are you ready?
世界一かわいい
World's cutest,
宇宙一かわいい
universe's cutest.
もっともっと声聞かせてよ
Let me hear your voice more and more.
脇見はダメ
No looking away.
オッケー！
Okay!
まばたきもかわいい
Even your blinking is cute,
存在がかわいい
your very existence is cute.
もっともっと惹きつけさせて
Let me charm you more and more.
ご褒美は
The reward is...
目を閉じて チュッ
close your eyes... Mwah!
歌ってくれてサンキュー
Thank you for singing.
笑顔をくれてサンキュー
Thank you for giving me your smile.
生きててよかったって思った
It made me feel so glad to be alive.
ちょっとのミスは愛嬌
A little mistake is just charm,
だけどやる気は最強
but my motivation is the strongest.
競い合って 高め合って
Competing and improving together,
せーので行こう！
let's go together!
苦手からずっと逃げてちゃ 愛は届かないから
If you keep running from what you're bad at, love won't reach you.
だから何度も 何度も挑もう
So let's challenge it over and over again.
楽しんじゃおう
Let's just have fun.
あざとくてかわいい
Cunningly cute,
最高にかわいい
the absolute cutest.
私だけをロックオン
Lock on to only me.
脇見はダメ
No looking away.
オッケー！
Okay!
動いてもかわいい
Cute even when moving,
存在がかわいい
your very existence is cute.
ずっとずっと惹きつけさせて
Let me charm you forever and ever.
輝くから
Because I'll shine.
約束ね
Promise?
上手に歌えてるかな
I wonder if I'm singing well.
上手に踊れてるかな
I wonder if I'm dancing well.
間違うの怖くなるけど
I get scared of making mistakes, but...
できる できる できる できる そうだ
I can do it, I can do it, I can do it, I can do it. That's right.
信じてくれる人がいる
There are people who believe in me.
この歌で君と繋がっていられる
Through this song, I can stay connected with you.
忘れられないストーリー 描いていこう
Let's draw an unforgettable story together.
行くよ！
Here we go!
世界一かわいい
World's cutest,
宇宙一かわいい
universe's cutest.
もっともっと声聞かせてよ
Let me hear your voice more and more.
脇見はダメ
No looking away.
オッケー！
Okay!
まばたきもかわいい
Even your blinking is cute,
存在がかわいい
your very existence is cute.
もっともっと惹きつけさせて
Let me charm you more and more.
ご褒美は
The reward is...
目を閉じて チュッ
close your eyes... Mwah!
現役アイドル中～
Geneki Idol Chu~
作詞：渡辺翔 / 作曲：渡辺翔 / 編曲：倉内竜一
Lyrics: Sho Watanabe / Composition: Sho Watanabe / Arrangement: Ryuichi Kurauchi
今日も鏡をチェック
Checking the mirror today too,
最高の笑顔届ける
to deliver the best smile.
才能に甘えないの
I won't rely on talent,
努力が大事よ
effort is what matters.
ちゃんとお勉強して
I study properly,
ちゃんとお片付けする
and I tidy up properly.
舞台では私はそうアイドルだもん
On stage, yes, I am an idol.
好きなタイプは私
Your favorite type is "me"?
答え大好きでも
Even if you say you love me...
真面目一直線
You're earnest,
ぴったりの君だけど 今じゃない
and perfect for me, but not right now.
（待ってて！）
(Wait for me!)
愛情はもっとあなただけど
My affection for you is growing, but...
君だけのものになれないの
I can't belong only to you.
（ああ ごめん）
(Ah, sorry)
いつまでも好きでいて 約束よ
Keep loving me forever, promise?
（せーの！）
(One, two!)
わがままなお願いね みんなのものでいたい
It's a selfish request, isn't it? I want to belong to everyone.
それでも私のこと 好きですか？
Even so, do you still love me?
（大好きだー！）
(I love you!)
ピンク色のフリフリ スポットライト浴びて
In pink ruffles, bathed in the spotlight.
いつかきっとね 君だけの私に
Someday, surely, I'll be yours alone.
今はもっと歌いたい
Right now, I want to sing more.
現役アイドル中
While I'm an active idol.
原石アイドルちゅう～
Diamond in the Rough Idolizing
#夏色まつり誕生祭2025
#NatsuiroMatsuriBirthdayLive2025
ずっとワクワクなのよ
I'm always so excited
お菓子配るのもして
Even handing out sweets,
お気に入りパクしちゃうんだ
I'll munch on my favorites
キラキラメイクは今日もバッチリ
My sparkly makeup is perfect again today
やっと君と出会えた
I finally got to meet you
ちょっと話せるだけなのになんか
Even if we just talk a bit, somehow...
あぁ多分私早起きして
Ah, I probably woke up early
二人の時間を楽しみにしてるから
Because I was looking forward to our time together
握手会コンサート会いに来て
Handshake events, concerts, come see me
君のハッピーなその顔ずっと覚えているわ
I'll remember your happy face forever
今週も来週も会いたいな
I want to see you this week and next week too
おしゃれな洋服も準備して待ってるね
I'll be waiting with cute clothes ready
愛残っても頑張る君の姿は
Even if love is left over, seeing you try your best
いつまでも好きでいる
I'll always love that
オフィシャル両想い
Officially mutual love
あした私と混ぜた一人にありがとう
Thank you to the person who combined with me tomorrow
こんなにキュートな私出来ちゃうもん
Because I can be this cute
クルクルドレスもキラリ回ってる
My dress is spinning around with a sparkle
いくつになってもこのままここで輝く
No matter how old I get, I'll keep shining right here
ねぇねぇ教えて
Hey, hey, tell me
なーつーも今日も可愛い？
Is Natsu cute today too?
可愛いよー！
You're cute!
いつまでも好きでいて
Keep loving me forever
約束よ
It's a promise
私だって君のことずっとずっと大好き
I love you so, so much too
一生私のこと好きですか
Will you love me for the rest of your life?
ピンク色のフリフリスパトライト浴びて
Bathed in pink frilly spotlights
いつかきっとね君だけの私に
Someday for sure, I'll be yours alone
今はまだ歌いたい
Right now, I still want to sing
原石アイドルちゅう
Diamond in the rough idolizing
わぁー！
Waaah!
みんなー！せーの！こんばんわっしょーい！
Everyone! One, two! Konbanwasshoi!
どうもホロライブの清楚担当
I'm Hololive's purity representative,
みんなのアイドル、夏色まつりです！
everyone's idol, Natsuiro Matsuri!
ということで今年もやってきました！
And so, the time has come again this year!
遅ればせながらの生誕、誕生祭でございますよ
It's my belated birthday celebration!
まつりちゃんの誕生日は7月の22日
Matsuri-chan's birthday is July 22nd,
なんですけども、まあ、あの周年が6月ということで
but since my anniversary is in June,
毎年11月にやらしていただいております
I hold this every year in November.
なので今日、実質誕生日でございますね！はい！
So today is practically my birthday! Yes!
おめでとう、ありがとうございます！
Happy birthday! Thank you so much!
そして本日のハッシュタグはこちら！ドドドドドン！
And here's today's hashtag! Drumroll, please!
夏色まつり誕生祭2025でございます！
Natsuiro Matsuri Birthday Live 2025!
いっぱいツイートしてトレンドに入れてあげてください、お願いします！
Please tweet a lot and help it trend, I'm counting on you!
あのスクショとかもね、撮っていただいたりとか
You can take screenshots and things like that,
あとツイートしてくれたらまつりちゃんが後でエゴサーチさせていただきますので
and if you tweet them, I'll go vanity searching for them later.
ぜひよろしくお願いしますね、見ちゃうよ見ちゃうよー！
So please do that, I'll be watching, I'll be watching!
はい！そしてね、まあ、皆さんもうお気づきかなと思います！
Yes! And well, I think you've all noticed by now!
本日のタイトル「アイドル革命進行中！今日の主役は夢の途中」
As the title "Idol Revolution in Progress! Today's Protagonist is Mid-Dream" suggests...
本日はアイドルさんの曲をたくさん詰め込んだ
today I've packed in lots of idol songs.
超とってもとっても可愛くて、ポップでキュートでワクワクするようなライブになっていますので
It's going to be a super, super cute, pop, and exciting live concert,
最後まで楽しんでいってくださいね！よろしくお願いします！
so please enjoy it until the very end! Here we go!
コメントでもサイリウムを振ったりとか、可愛いよって言っちゃったりとか、たくさんしてくださいね！
Please wave your penlights in the comments and say I'm cute, do it a lot!
ということでこの後は皆さんお待ちかねのゲストパート！
And now, the guest part you've all been waiting for!
やったー！
Yay!
はい、ちょっとね...
Well, actually...
あの、まつりちゃん本家ダンスとかが凄く大好きなので
Um, Matsuri-chan really loves the original dances, so...
あの、レッスンでね、「お願い！やらせてください！」って言って
At my lessons, I was like, "Please! Let me do it!"
フォーメーションとかもね、含め、みんなには頑張ってもらっていますので
And including the formations and everything, I'm having everyone work hard on them,
あの、君の推しがもしいたら、褒めてあげてください！
so if your oshi is here, please give them some praise!
ということで、え、ゲストパート準備してきちゃいますね！
So, I'm going to go get ready for the guest part!
じゃあ、みんなワクワクってコメントして待ってて。
Alright everyone, please comment "waku waku" while you wait.
じゃ、いってきまーい！
Well, I'm off!
ワクワク、ワクワク、ワクワクワクワクワクワク
Waku waku, waku waku, waku waku waku waku...
サクラあっぱれーしょん
Sakura Apparition
作詞・作曲：玉屋2060% (Wienners)
Lyrics & Composition: Tamaya 2060% (Wienners)
まつり
Matsuri
ヘイヨーPMPMフロム秋葉原TO A-B-A
Hey yo, PMPM from Akihabara to A-B-A
さぁさ寄ってらっしゃい見てらっしゃい　もう一切合切やっちゃいな
Come one, come all, take a look! Just go ahead and do everything!
ありったけの可愛いたのしいこと詰め込んで
Pack in all the cute and fun things you've got
さぁヨイショヨイショお船に乗って　いざ出航じゃ！
Now, heave-ho! Get on the ship! It's time to set sail!
ヘイヨーPMPMフロムジャパニーズホットエリア
Hey yo, PMPM from the Japanese hot area
みんな元気ですか？恋させてあげて！ハイ電波！電波！
Is everyone doing good? Let them fall in love! High-denpa! Denpa!
ありがサンキュー準備はバッチリのよるのひるの
Ariga-thank you! Preparation is perfect, night and day
さぁ今から二回お船に乗って　いざ出航じゃ！
Now, from here, get on the ship twice! It's time to set sail!
さぁみんなダンスダンスダンス　ほら　足踏んで
Now everyone, dance, dance, dance! Come on, stomp your feet!
ミラーがヒラリ　格好つけてもパッパッパ
The mirror flutters! Even if you try to look cool, it's pa-pa-pa!
めちゃくちゃな呪文見たり　それが僕らにとってのファンタジー
Seeing crazy spells... that's our fantasy
シュートシュート感じるんだ　酔ってるんだ
Shoot, shoot, feel it! Getting drunk on it!
ソレソレソレソレ
Sore sore sore sore!
シッシッシッ胸を張っては汗たらり
Shi shi shi, puffing out our chests, sweat trickling down
ずっと知ってもコジコジ逆方向
Even if you know, go the opposite way, coji-coji
青春はそれでいいのだ
That's what youth is all about!
勘違いも味方にしちゃうのだ
Let's make even misunderstandings our allies!
ジパング日本　踊れ日本　ソレソレソレ　よいしょー！
Zipangu, Japan! Dance, Japan! Sore sore sore, heave-ho!
珍道中　さぁどこまでも
An eccentric journey, let's go everywhere
ほらパワフル全開で突き抜けろ
Look, break through with full power!
あっちもこっちもそっちも　まつりだワッショイ
Here, there, and everywhere, it's a Matsuri festival, wasshoi!
あっぱれあっぱれアドベンチャー
Splendid, splendid adventure!
ヤマトナデシコ　エマ　不思議な言霊
Yamato Nadeshiko, Emma, mysterious power of words
ハッハッハッ
Ha ha ha!
奇想天外　さぁいつまでも
Bizarre and fantastic, let's go forever
神様仏様うさぎ様
God, Buddha, and Mr. Rabbit
月に祈って拝んで　ヒニを思って
Praying and worshiping the moon, thinking of the day
半端な気持ちを断ち切って
Cutting off any half-hearted feelings
とりあえず今は黙ってついてこい
For now, just shut up and follow me!
フォローミー
Follow me!
オーオー　君の未来を明るく照らすなんて
Oh oh! To brightly illuminate your future...
お茶の子さいさいさい！
It's a piece of cake-cake-cake!
百花繚乱　大和撫子たちよ
Profusion of flowers, oh Yamato Nadeshikos!
どでかい花火を上げましょうね
Let's set off some huge fireworks!
ほら踊る阿呆に見る阿呆
Look, there are fools who dance and fools who watch
同じ阿呆なら踊らにゃ損損！
If we're both fools, we might as well dance!
さぁみんなダンスダンスダンス　ほら　足踏んで
Now everyone, dance, dance, dance! Come on, stomp your feet!
おへそチラリ　くつ脱いだらソクソク破れてる
A glimpse of the belly button! When I take off my shoes, the socks are torn!
ドタバタなこのステージ　これが私にとっての誠意
This hectic stage, this is my sincerity
一生懸命羽ばたくんだ　聞こえるんだ
Flapping my wings with all my might! I can hear it!
ソレソレソレソレ
Sore sore sore sore!
シッシッシッ胸を張って涙キラリ
Shi shi shi, puffing out my chest, a glint of tears
強がってもキュンキュン苦しいの
Even if I act tough, my heart is aching!
乙女はそれでいいのだ　マイナスも味方にしちゃうのだ
That's what girls are all about! Let's make even negatives our allies!
全力愛してんだ　みんな大好きだ
I love you with all my heart! I love you all!
ダダダダダ　ブレイクダウン！
Da-da-da-da-da, break down!
珍道中　さぁどこまでも
An eccentric journey, let's go everywhere
ほらパワフル全開で突き抜けろ
Look, break through with full power!
あっちもこっちもそっちも　まつりだワッショイ
Here, there, and everywhere, it's a Matsuri festival, wasshoi!
あっぱれあっぱれアドベンチャー
Splendid, splendid adventure!
ヤマトナデシコ　エマ　不思議な言霊
Yamato Nadeshiko, Emma, mysterious power of words
ハッハッハッ
Ha ha ha!
奇想天外　さぁいつまでも
Bizarre and fantastic, let's go forever
神様仏様うさぎ様
God, Buddha, and Mr. Rabbit
月に祈って拝んで　ヒニを思って
Praying and worshiping the moon, thinking of the day
半端な気持ちを断ち切って
Cutting off any half-hearted feelings
とりあえず今は黙ってついてこい
For now, just shut up and follow me!
フォローミー
Follow me!
オーオー　君の未来を明るく照らすなんて
Oh oh! To brightly illuminate your future...
お茶の子さいさいさい！
It's a piece of cake-cake-cake!
よいしょ！
Heave-ho!
はい！満月の下で踊りましょう
Yes! Let's dance under the full moon!
桜舞い散る季節に歌いましょう
Let's sing in the season of falling cherry blossoms!
君といつかまた出会うその日まで
Until the day we meet again sometime
お空にお天道様　お星様　あなた様
To the sun in the sky, the stars, and to you
わーっ！みんなでバイバイさよならー！
Wah! Everyone, bye-bye, goodbye!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
時間たてば 事務的にやってくる
As time passes, it comes around mechanically
明日なんて 我々の明日じゃない
Tomorrow isn't our tomorrow
逃げたい じゃあどこに
I want to run away, so then where to?
逃げれば いいのかな
Is it okay if I run away?
曖昧な 場所では
In an ambiguous place
何にも 変われない
Nothing can change
立ち向かえとか やり直せるとか
Face it, or start over
間違った道を
The wrong path
何度も やり直さされる
We are made to start over again and again
あなた一体誰ですか？
Who on earth are you?
論点ずれてる
Missing the point
人たち なんか押しのけて
Pushing aside those kinds of people
自分の道
My own path
作らなくちゃ
I must create
“失敗しない”なんて
“I won't fail”
契約を人は誰とも結んではいない
No one has made a contract like that with anyone
“幸せになります”とは皆いつか
“I will be happy” is a promise everyone
昔 大事な人と 約束したはずだ
Must have made with someone important long ago
大人になるために
In order to become an adult
早く忘れることだけ覚え
Just learn to forget quickly
無理に目を背けたら
If you forcibly look away
10年後の君を救えないよ
You won't be able to save your future self 10 years from now
全部自分が悪いと
To you, who blames yourself
責める君に伝えたい
For everything, I want to tell you
同じ言葉を人に
No one can blame you
言わない君を誰も責められない
For not saying the same words to others
逃げない じゃあどこに
I won't run away, so then where to?
向かえば いいのかな
Where should I head?
辛さの 根源を
The root of the pain
見つめ直せる場所
A place to look at it again
いきなり
Suddenly
空を飛ぶ 方法なんて知らない
I don't know the way to fly in the sky
悪と暇の
No one should go back and forth
行き来は誰ももうしないで！
Between evil and idleness anymore!
生きろとか よみがえれとか
“Live,” or “be reborn”
もういい もういい 逆に逃げて
Enough, enough, conversely run away
もういいんだよとかいう
And to say “it's already fine,”
私は一体誰ですか？
Who on earth am I?
わかってくれている
The sparkle in the eyes
瞳の輝きが
That understand me
消えてないって
There are people who proved
証明してくれた人たちがいる
That it hasn't disappeared
時間たてば 事務的にやってくる
As time passes, it comes around mechanically
明日なんて 我々の明日じゃない
Tomorrow isn't our tomorrow
足に訊ねる 走れるか
Asking your feet, “Can you run?”
指に訊ねる 開けるか
Asking your fingers, “Can you open?”
体温に訊ねる
Asking your body temperature
血潮で導いて いけるだろうか
“Can I be guided by my blood?”
始まりの合図は他の
I don't want anyone else to decide
誰にも決めさせたくない
The signal to start
教科書の先の現代は
Because we will create the modern world
我々が作ってゆくから
Beyond the textbooks
だから逃げない
So I won't run away
私は逃げない
I won't run away
逃げたい君を
I won't leave you
置いてはゆかない
Who wants to run away behind
じゃなきゃ意味ない！
Otherwise it's meaningless!
離したいことない
I have nothing I want to let go of
顔を見なくなって
Even if I don't see your face,
君を知ってる
I know you
苦しめる 渦の中
Inside the vortex of suffering
頭脳の目 広げて
Opening the eyes of the mind
別の角度で 見てごらん
Look at it from a different angle
そこだけ 逃げないで
Don't run away from just that
時間たてば 事務的にやってくる
As time passes, it comes around mechanically
明日なんて 我々の明日じゃない
Tomorrow isn't our tomorrow
とくべちゅ、して
Give me something special
Oh baby 「I love you」じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" isn't enough
一番　大事がいい
Being your number one is best
君が作るオリジナルの
Give me your original,
特別、チューして。
special kiss.
眩しくて目が覚めて
Waking up to the brightness
愛おしく思ってよ
Think of me dearly
眠り姫のように優しく口付けて
Kiss me gently like a Sleeping Beauty
ゴミめいたこの世界
In this world that seems like trash
ピュアがかかる君がいる
There's you, covered in purity
全てに触れずに2人だけでいよう
Let's be alone together, without touching anything else
私のこと独占して
Monopolize me
君だけのモノになってもいい
I don't mind becoming yours alone
なんでもあの日の一言もない　気付いてね
Notice that there's not even a single word from that day
Oh baby 「I love you」じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" isn't enough
君の「特別」にして
Make me your "special one"
ねえもっと Give me a kiss もう私は
Hey, give me a kiss more, I'm already
君でいっぱいよ
filled with you
ほどけないリボン結び
An untieable ribbon knot
小指ギュッて縛って
Tie our pinkies tight
そうよ一生一緒がいいもん
That's right, I want to be together forever
トクベチュが欲しい
I want a special kiss
2人きり週末は
On weekends with just the two of us
奏でてよハーモニー
Let's play a harmony
流れ星見たら私を想ってほしい
I want you to think of me when you see a shooting star
あまままな君なのに
Even though you're so sweet
広い街吸い込まれ
Swallowed by the wide city
戦う姿に大きいハナマルだね
Your fighting figure gets a big gold star
好きなところ、優しいとこ。
What I like about you is your kindness.
嫌いなとこも、優しいとこ。
What I hate about you is also your kindness.
誰にもあげない　私だけ独り占め！
I won't give you to anyone, I'll keep you all to myself!
う～だって今までの人と　同じはいらないんです
Cause I don't want to be the same as everyone else before
ねえもっと Give me more love 私のため　生きてほしいんです
Hey, give me more love, I want you to live for me
だからウサギと私は　寂しくさせないで
So don't make me and the rabbit feel lonely
そんなんじゃ束縛じゃないわ　苦しいのが好き
That's not a restraint, I like the pain
ショートケーキイチゴみたいに　座ってもいい？
Can I sit like a strawberry on a shortcake?
赤く甘い恋だもん
It's a red, sweet love
誰かにあげた大好きも
Even the "I love you"s you gave to someone else
返してもらって全部私に
Get them back and give them all to me
ちょーだい
Give it to me
もっと！
More!
君は神様が作る奇跡のようなヒト
You are a person like a miracle made by God
拗ねた顔もその寝顔も
Your sulky face and your sleeping face
守ってあげるね
I'll protect them for you
Oh baby 「I love you」じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" isn't enough
君の「特別」にして
Make me your "special one"
ねえもっと Give me a kiss もう私は
Hey, give me a kiss more, I'm already
君でいっぱいよ
filled with you
ほどけないリボン結び
An untieable ribbon knot
小指ギュッて縛って
Tie our pinkies tight
ねえ baby 最初で最後の
Hey baby, make this our first and last
トクベチュにしてね
special kiss
ぱぴぷぺPOP！ 作詞・作曲：玉屋2060% (Wienners)
Papipu Pe POP! Lyrics/Music: Tamaya 2060% (Wienners)
ミルクで乾杯～
Cheers with milk!
ちょっと待ったら甘い～
Wait a bit and it's sweet!
レンジでチンしてあったかい
Warm it up in the microwave
レッツゴー　ぱぴぷぺPOP　YO!
Let's go, Papipu Pe POP YO!
人生万歳
Long live life
この先10年安泰
Safe for the next 10 years
盛れバズったら半端な～い
If it goes viral, it'll be insane
レッツゴー　ぱぴぷぺPOP!
Let's go, Papipu Pe POP!
ピュンピュンです
Pyun-pyun!
ギュンギュンです
Gyun-gyun!
ルンルンです
Lun-lun!
ハッピーです
Happy!
問題ないっす半端ないっす我らディスコティックなバンビーナ
No problem, it's insane, we're discotheque bambinas
テキトーです
Whatever!
イージーです
Easy!
曖昧です
Vague!
ずっとこうやって
Let's keep going like this
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じでポップに生きていこう
And live pop in a Papipu Pe Po way
ぱぴぷぺPOP!
Papipu Pe POP!
Hi! Hi!
ぱぴぷぺPOP!
Papipu Pe POP!
Hi! Hi!
毎日毎日パーティー
Every day is a party
パーティーピーポー
Party people
横ノリ縦ノリ悪ノリで　Oh yeah
Swaying side to side, up and down, and being mischievous, oh yeah
映画のキャストみたいに
Just like a movie cast
ボンキュのボンなりパーティー
A curvy party
ハジけて　smile delight
Bursting with smile delight
なんでスネてんの？
Why are you sulking?
(うるさい！)
(Shut up!)
なんで泣いてんの？
Why are you crying?
(あっちいって！)
(Go away!)
なんでなんで？
Why, why?
だってだって
Because, because
女の子だもん
I'm a girl, after all
なんで帰っちゃうの？
Why are you going home?
（触んないで！）
(Don't touch me!)
なんで怒ってんの？
Why are you angry?
（あーもう）
(Ah, jeez)
わかってよ
Understand me
言わなくてもわかってよ
Understand me without me saying it
わかってよ
Understand me
どうもごめん
I'm so sorry
やっぱ好きー！
I still love you!
めんどくさっ
How bothersome
ぴゅんぴゅんです ぴゅんぴゅんです
Pyun-pyun! Pyun-pyun!
るんるんです きゃっきゃーです
Run-run! Kyah-kyah!
ハッピーです
I'm happy
問題ないっす 半端ないっす
No problem, it's incredible
我々ディスコティックなバンビーナ
We're discotheque bambinas
テキトーです イージーです
Going with the flow, it's easy
曖昧です ずっとこうやって
It's ambiguous, keep going like this
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じでポップに生きていこう
Living life in a 'Pa-pi-pu-pe-po' kind of way
ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po
Hi!
Hi! Hi!
ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po
Hi!
Hi! Hi!
ぱっと咲いて shy
Blooming suddenly, I'm shy
ピアニシモで kiss
A kiss in pianissimo
ブロウアップ yo
Blow up, yo
ペプシ飲んで「お～」
Drink some Pepsi and 'Ohhh'
ポップに踊ろう
Let's dance in a pop way
さぁ Let's Go.
Now, let's go.
Funny Funny time!
ぺっぺけぺっぺ ぺっぺけぺっぺ
Peppeke-peppe, peppeke-peppe
きれいです 3・2・1
You're beautiful, 3, 2, 1
ぺっぺけぺっぺ ぺっぺけぺっぺ
Peppeke-peppe, peppeke-peppe
おこです 3・2・1
I'm angry, 3, 2, 1
ぺっぺけぺっぺ ぺっぺけぺっぺ
Peppeke-peppe, peppeke-peppe
笑顔で 3・2・1
With a smile, 3, 2, 1
ぺっぺけぺっぺ ぺっぺけぺっぺ
Peppeke-peppe, peppeke-peppe
安らげ 3・2・1
Be at peace, 3, 2, 1
なんかいい感じ
Feels kind of good
（もしもーし？）
(Hello?)
なんか嬉しいね
I'm kind of happy
（どうしたん？）
(What's wrong?)
なんかなんか
Somehow, somehow
やっぱやっぱ
Still, still
女の子だもん
I'm a girl, after all
なんかハッピーです
I'm kind of happy
（うん、それな？）
(Yeah, exactly)
なんか超絶です
I'm kind of transcendent
（あーんもう）
(Ah, jeez)
幸せです！聞いてよ幸せです！
I'm happy! Listen, I'm happy!
ちょっと話してたらさ
I was talking a bit and then...
聞いてー！
Listen!
へーそうなんだ…
Heh, is that so...
最高です 超です ミラクルです
The best, superb, a miracle
チョベリグです ハイパーです
So very good, hyper
とんでもないっす 尋常ないっす
Unbelievable, extraordinary
我々アーティスティックなバンビーナ
We're artistic bambinas
ちょっとだけ ポンクラです
Just a bit of a blockhead
大概です ずっとこうやって
For the most part, keep going like this
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じでポップに生きていこう
Living life in a 'Pa-pi-pu-pe-po' kind of way
ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po
ミルクで乾杯～
A toast with milk!
砂糖混ぜたらあまーい
Mixed with sugar, it's sweet
レンジでチンしてあったかい
Heat it in the microwave and it's warm
Let's Go! ぱぴぷぺぽ
Let's Go! Pa-pi-pu-pe-po
人生万歳～
Long live life!
この先10年安泰～
Peace for the next 10 years
盛れてバズったらはんぱな～い
Looking good and going viral, it's incredible
Let's Go! ぱぴぷぺぽ
Let's Go! Pa-pi-pu-pe-po
ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po
ぱぴぷぺぽっぴー！
Pa-pi-pu-pe-poppin'!
ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po
愛チュセヨ
Give me love
Lovin' you
アモーレ
Amore
アミーゴ
Amigo
ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po
ABCDEFGHIJKLMNOP Poppin'
Be Poppin'! Poppin'! Poppin'! Poppin'!
ぱ！ぱ！ぱ！ぱ！
Pa! Pa! Pa! Pa!
最大級 最高級 最上級
Greatest, highest, superlative
ハイスペックな人生です
A high-spec life
アイラブユー アイフォーユー
I love you, I for you
だけど君がいないと寂しいな
But it's lonely without you
ほんとはね やっぱりね
Actually, you see, after all
結局ね ずっとこうやって
In the end, keep going like this
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じでポップに生きていこう
Living life in a 'Pa-pi-pu-pe-po' kind of way
ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po
ぴゅんぴゅんです ぴゅんぴゅんです
Pyun-pyun! Pyun-pyun!
るんるんです きゃっきゃーです
Run-run! Kyah-kyah!
ハッピーです
I'm happy
問題ないっす 半端ないっす
No problem, it's incredible
我々ディスコティックなバンビーナ
We're discotheque bambinas
テキトーです イージーです
Going with the flow, it's easy
曖昧です ずっとこうやって
It's ambiguous, keep going like this
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じでポップに生きていこう
Living life in a 'Pa-pi-pu-pe-po' kind of way
ポップにエンジョイ
Enjoy in a pop way
あれこれどれそれ楽しいね
This and that, everything is fun
Hi!
Hi! Hi!
ポップにエンジョイ
Enjoy in a pop way
あれこれどれそれ楽しいね
This and that, everything is fun
Hi!
Hi! Hi!
ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po
Poppin',
POP!
みんなー！ゲストパートどうだったー？
Everyone! How was the guest part?
可愛かった？ありがとうございます。
Was it cute? Thank you very much.
ということでね、すごい続けてやってしまったんですが、
So, I did them all in a row,
まず「サクラ・アプレシエイション」は、AZKiちゃんとルーナちゃんとリリカに出てもらいました。
First, for 'Sakura Appreciation', I had AZKi-chan, Luna-chan, and Ririka join me.
なんかすごい桜というか、春っぽいね、ピンクーな感じのメンバーをね、呼びました。
I invited members who felt very 'cherry blossom' or spring-like, with a pink vibe.
リリカすごい頑張ってたよなぁ。
Ririka really worked hard, didn't she?
すごいね、練習中も「あー！できないー！」って言いながらね、頑張ってたリリカ。
She was saying 'Ah! I can't do it!' even during practice, but she did her best.
そして次「逃げない」ね。
And next, 'Nigenai'.
「逃げない」はちょっと結構古めの曲なんですけど、
'Nigenai' is a bit of an older song,
まつりがすごーいすごい大好きで一番推していた「ゆるめるモ！」さんの楽曲で、
It's a song by 'Yurumerumo!', who I really love and supported the most,
あの、ここで歌えてすごく嬉しかったです。ありがとうございますね。
And I was so happy to be able to sing it here. Thank you.
そして「特別して」は、もう難しかった！
And 'Tokubetsu Shite' was just so difficult!
すごい難しかったんだから。
It was really hard.
だってさ、1番と2番さ、あのサビの振りも違うしさ、めちゃ難しかったよ。
Because the choreography for the chorus is different in the first and second verses, it was super hard.
や、=LOVEさんの曲は毎回難しいけど、すごい踊ってて楽しいでございますね。
Well, =LOVE's songs are always difficult, but they're really fun to dance to.
はい、そして「ぱぴぷぺPOP!」。
Yes, and 'Papipupe POP!'.
これ、あの、ずっとこうやってるからすごい疲れて、あの汗だくになった。
Since I was doing this the whole time, I got really tired and covered in sweat.
もうすごかったよ。
It was intense.
練習中の時も汗だくすぎて「ちょっと待って、ちょっと疲れた」とか言ってね、
Even during practice, I was sweating so much and saying, 'Wait a sec, I'm a bit tired',
みんなでわちゃわちゃしながらね、練習もしましたけど、すごい楽しかったでございます。
We practiced while messing around together, and it was a lot of fun.
そして、ちょっと紹介できてなかったこちらのステージ！じゃーん！可愛いー！
And, this stage that I hadn't introduced yet! Ta-da! It's so cute!
すごい可愛くね、作っていただきました。
They made it look very cute for me.
「アイドルソングたちばかりなので、アイドルステージっていう感じにしてください」って言ってね、
"Since I'm singing only idol songs, I asked them to make it look like an idol stage."
こんな感じになりましたよ。
And this is how it turned out!
あの、提灯もあるけどさ、なんかすごい、あの、主張しすぎないというか、いい意味でね。
There are lanterns too, but they're not too over-the-top, in a good way.
あの、なんかパステルなピンクとか、まあこれ色変わるんですけど、すごい可愛い感じにしてくれて。
With the pastel pink and everything—the colors actually change—it's so cute.
風船もね、これね、色変わるんですよね実はね。
And the balloons change colors too, actually.
なんかちょっとその辺も注目していただきたいなと思いますね。
I hope you all pay attention to those details too.
めっちゃ可愛いでしょ。
It's super cute, isn't it?
あの、あとで一個だけ持って帰らせてもらおうかなと思います。
I think I'll take one of these home with me later.
はい、そして！あのごめん、みんな気づいてなかったかなと思うんですけど、
Okay, and! Sorry, I don't know if you noticed yet, but...
あのね、まつりすがいるわけですよ。
The Matsuris are here!
そう、あのね、周年、一期生の周年ライブの時にはいなかったんですよ。
Yeah, they weren't at the 1st Gen Anniversary Live.
ね、エビフライオンがいたの、代わりに。
Ebiflyon was there instead.
他のさ、はあとんとかはさ、あの、ちゃんとはあとんとしていたのに。リスナーさんの姿でいたのに。
The others, like the Haatons, were there as themselves. As the listeners.
まつりだけね、まつりすがいなくて、エビフライオンだったんで、今回、あの、よかったね、これ。
Only I didn't have Matsuris; it was Ebiflyon. So I'm glad they could make it this time.
ということで、早速、続いての曲いきましょうか。
So, let's move on to the next song right away.
続いての、続いて、アイドルソングでございますよ。
The next one is... 'Idol Song'!
それでは聞いてください、アイドルソング。
Please listen: 'Idol Song.'
ねえ　アイドルになりたい
Hey, I want to be an idol
すっごい　愛をあげたい
I want to give you so much love
この命の使い道を　君に愛されたい
For the purpose of this life, I want to be loved by you
はい！えくぼは恋の落とし穴
Yes! Dimples are a pitfall for love
夢中にさせちゃうぞ！
I'm gonna make you obsessed with me!
埼玉県から来ました　フレッシュレモンになりたいの
I'm from Saitama Prefecture, and I want to be a fresh lemon!
ファンの方が恋人です　真面目なアイドル　真面目にアイドル
The fans are my lovers! A serious idol, seriously being an idol
年中無休　24時間ずっと笑顔で　うさちゃんピース！
Smiling 24/7, year-round! Usachan Peace!
はい！あなたの心にハッピーバースデー
Yes! Happy Birthday to your heart!
あなたのハートにアクセスします
I'm accessing your heart
みんなのドキドキにシュートします
I'll shoot right into everyone's pounding hearts
なんでもいいからレスください
I don't care what it is, just give me a response!
ハゲ気味の皆様ー！
To all of you going a bit bald—!
よし、今日も可愛い！小指ー！
Alright, cute again today! Pinky finger!
ねえ　アイドルになりたい
Hey, I want to be an idol
ずっとはわからないけど
I don't know if it'll be forever
幸せに満ちてるシャンプーの香りを見つけたの
But I found a shampoo scent that's full of happiness
歌で人の気持ち　明るくできるように
So I can brighten people's feelings with my songs
きっと人生にくじけてる　人がいると思うから
Because I'm sure there are people discouraged by life
はい　好きっていいなよ！　はい　もっと簡単に！
Yes, say "I love you"! Yes, keep it simple!
はい　好きっていいなよ！　はい　もっと叫べ！
Yes, say "I love you"! Yes, shout it louder!
はい　好きっていいなよ！　はい　もっと簡単に！
Yes, say "I love you"! Yes, keep it simple!
はい　好きっていいなよ！　はい　もっと叫べ！　イェーイ！
Yes, say "I love you"! Yes, shout it louder! Yay!
はい　めちゃくちゃ話すのが苦手
Yes, I'm super bad at talking
可愛い自分　気持ち悪い
My cute self is disgusting
世界のルール歌って踊って破壊する
Singing and dancing to destroy the world's rules
燃える闘魂燃える髪の毛　見た目は純白中身は真っ黒
Burning fighting spirit, burning hair! Pure white look, pitch-black heart
ちょっぴりおバカな小さな巨人　完成ショータイム！
A slightly silly little giant. Show time complete!
みるくとみゆきあを混ぜるだけ　あっという間にミルキー
Just mix milk and Miyukia, and instantly it's Milky!
ちちんぷいぷい魔法にかかれ　あ、かかっちゃった
Chichin-puipui, fall under my spell! Oh, you fell for it.
トイレなんて行ったことないよ　ピンクのマシュマロが出ます
I've never even been to a toilet! I produce pink marshmallows.
3時のおやつはマカロンがよき　ふわふわガール目指し中
Macarons are best for a 3 PM snack. Aiming to be a fluffy girl!
ねえ　アイドルが楽しい
Hey, being an idol is fun
いっぱい　愛がまわってる
So much love is going around
ステージから見る景色が　ずっと宝物さ
The view from the stage will always be my treasure
ねえ　もし君が尊い
Hey, if you're precious
失望しても君が
Even if you're disappointed
救うような分の幸せを　あげられていたかな
I wonder if I could give you enough happiness to save you
はい　好きっていいなよ！　はい　もっと大胆に！
Yes, say "I love you"! Yes, be more daring!
はい　好きっていいなよ！　はい　もっと叫べ！
Yes, say "I love you"! Yes, shout it louder!
はい　好きっていいなよ！　はい　もっと大胆に！
Yes, say "I love you"! Yes, be more daring!
はい　好きっていいなよ！　はい　もっと叫べ！　フゥー！
Yes, say "I love you"! Yes, shout it louder! Whoo!
はい　360度どこから見てもアイドル
Yes, an idol from any angle, 360 degrees!
出席番号ラッキーセブン　好きになってもいいですか？
Attendance number Lucky Seven! Is it okay if I love you?
僕の妹がこんなに可愛いわけがない　でしょ
My little sister can't be this cute... right?
ぷりっぷりピチピチでしょ　こんにちはメンギギ
So plump and fresh, right? Hello, Mengigi!
推せる愛せるランドセル
Supportable, lovable, Randoseru!
今日も明日も明後日も　キラキラパワー全開
Today, tomorrow, and the day after—sparkly power at full blast!
頑張って行ったー！
I'm gonna do my best!
みんなの目線はいただきまゆゆ
Everyone's eyes are on Mayuyu!
泣き虫で甘えん坊な　みんなの妹
A crybaby and a spoiled brat—everyone's little sister
ねえ　アイドルが楽しい
Hey, being an idol is fun
いっぱい　愛がまわってる
So much love is going around
ステージから見る景色が...
The view from the stage...
ずっと歌ってたいものさ
I want to keep singing forever
ねえアイドルになりたい
Hey, I want to become an idol
すごい愛をあげたい
I want to give you so much love
この命の使い方は
How to use this life...
君に愛されていたい
I want to be loved by you
好きでいよう　もっと簡単に
Let's keep loving, more easily
好きでいよう　もっと届けて
Let's keep loving, reach further
好きでいよう　もっと簡単に
Let's keep loving, more easily
好きでいよう　もっと届けて
Let's keep loving, reach further
好きでいよう　もっと大胆に
Let's keep loving, more boldly
好きでいよう　もっと届けて
Let's keep loving, reach further
好きでいよう　もっと大胆に
Let's keep loving, more boldly
好きでいよう　もっと叫べ
Let's keep loving, shout it louder
響け優しさ　絆　キラキラ輝け
Resonate kindness, bonds, shine brightly
頑張っていきまーしょい！
Let's do our best!
ワン... びっくりしたでしょ？
One... Surprised you, didn't I?
今日の私が昨日より可愛いなんて
That I'm even cuter today than yesterday
ちゅーぎゅー♡
作詞・作曲：大森靖子
Chu-Gyu♡
Lyrics & Composition: Seiko Oomori
ぎゅちゅぎゅちゅぎゅってして
Gyu-chu, gyu-chu, hug me tight
次の流行りは次の地雷
The next trend is the next landmine
踏まないように知っとかなくちゃ
I have to know so I don't step on it
でもぎゅってしたら大爆発
But if we hug, it's a big explosion
死にたい死にたい死にたくない
I want to die, want to die, don't want to die
知りたくないずっと閉じたら
I don't want to know, if I close up forever
すぐになぜなぜわからないだらけ
Suddenly it's full of why's and unknowns
今こそワンダラン
Now is the time for Wonderland
私 ちっ ちっ ちっ ちっ ちっ
Me, chi-chi-chi-chi-chi
ぎゅっ 私 ちっ ちっ ちっ ちっ ちっ
Gyu, me, chi-chi-chi-chi-chi
ぎゅっ
Gyu!
ぎゅっ！
過去最年少 未来最年少
Youngest in the past, youngest in the future
過去最大ラブ 未来各駅停車
Maximum love in the past, local train in the future
未来ギラチラ 福袋みたい
Future glittering and shimmering, like a lucky bag
好きな色が見えたからこれにしようかな
I saw my favorite color, so maybe I'll pick this
カプセラ イェーイ！
Capsella, yay!
ちゅーぎゅー
Chu-Gyu
ぎゅぎゅぎゅぎゅぎゅ！
Gyu-gyu-gyu-gyu-gyu!
予想はしないならしちゃう寿命
If I don't predict it, my lifespan will end
間違っても可愛くなれる寿命
Lifespan where I can become cute even if I'm wrong
一番可愛いときに死にたいなら
If you want to die when you're at your cutest,
全然死なないで
Then don't die at all
私 ちっ ちっ ちっ ちっ ちっ
Me, chi-chi-chi-chi-chi
ぎゅっ 私 ちっ ちっ ちっ ちっ ちっ
Gyu, me, chi-chi-chi-chi-chi
死んでる暇ない可愛いと言いたい
No time to die, I want to say I'm cute
過去最年少 未来最年少
Youngest in the past, youngest in the future
今最年少 未来全部入り
Youngest now, future is all-inclusive
好きな自分以外は無視して
Ignore everything except the self you like
ひたすら可愛く無敵な女の子でいよう
Let's just stay a cute and invincible girl
「何歳になっても可愛いね」じゃないの。
It's not "You're cute no matter how old you get."
こっちは努力して可愛いやっとんの。
I'm putting in the effort to be cute here.
何十何歳だったら可愛いの？
How many dozens of years old is cute?
本当にそんなの当たり前だもん。
Seriously, that's just common sense.
言わせないでよ。そっちが言って。
Don't make me say it. You say it.
「今日も可愛いね」
"You're cute today too."
でしょ？
Right?
今日も可愛いね
You're cute today too
可愛いね
You're cute
可愛い！
Cute!
今日も可愛い！
You're cute today!
私 今日も可愛いね
I'm cute today too, aren't I?
よし 今日も可愛いぞ
Alright, I'm cute today too!
未来ギラチラ お利口お祝い
Future glittering and shimmering, a good girl's celebration
覗き見しては元に戻して
Peeking and then putting it back
未来ギラチラ 怖いからこそ
Future glittering and shimmering, because it's scary
今思う存分強気に生きたい
I want to live aggressively to my heart's content now
過去最年少 未来最年少
Youngest in the past, youngest in the future
過去最大ラブ 未来各駅停車
Maximum love in the past, local train in the future
未来ギラチラ 福袋みたい
Future glittering and shimmering, like a lucky bag
好きな色が見えたからこれにしようかな
I saw my favorite color, so maybe I'll pick this
カプセラ イェーイ！
Capsella, yay!
ちゅーぎゅー
Chu-Gyu
ぎゅぎゅぎゅぎゅぎゅ！
Gyu-gyu-gyu-gyu-gyu!
カプセラ
Capsella
君に恋々恋のエスオーエス
Love-love-loving you, SOS
ずっと胸が苦しいんです
My heart has been aching this whole time
早くレスキュー好きのテレパシーに
Quick, rescue me, through the telepathy of love
早く気づいて
Please notice quickly
SOS
作曲：睦月周平 / 作詞：下地悠
Composition: Shuhei Mutsuki / Lyrics: Yu Shimoji
初めて会った時から
From the moment we first met
ハートが震えてたんだよ
My heart was trembling
無意識に意識しちゃう
I'm unconsciously conscious of you
この感じはきっと重症で
This feeling must be a serious case
求め合うだけで顔が熱いの
Just seeking each other makes my face hot
話しかけられて頭がパニック
When you talk to me, my head panics
全部抱きしめて
Hold my whole heart tight
君との相性診断 星占いなら ゾッコン ゾッコン
Our compatibility according to the stars says we're a perfect match
友達なんかじゃないよ ときメいてる
We're not just friends, my heart is racing
君に Falling 恋の SOS ずっと胸が苦しいんです
Falling for you, a love SOS, my chest has been aching for so long
早く Rescue 恋のテレパシー 早く気付いて
Rescue me quickly, love telepathy, please notice soon
これは Falling 恋の SOS もっと君に近づきたい
This is falling, a love SOS, I want to get closer to you
終わらせて 片想い My heart 全部抱きしめて
End this unrequited love, hold my whole heart tight
SOS
君が好きな音楽や 映画のことリサーチして
I research the music and movies you like
SNS見るたびに いいね押すの アピールだよ
Every time I see your SNS, I press "like" to show my interest
もっともっともっともっと君のこと考えて 悶えながら 枕 濡らした
Thinking about you more and more, writhing around and soaking my pillow with tears
明日は何の服着ていこうかな
I wonder what clothes I should wear tomorrow
君 想うだけで なんか照れる
Just thinking of you makes me blush
君の名前を呼べば ただそれだけでも Dreaming dreaming
Just calling your name makes me feel like I'm dreaming
溺れそうな私は さあ 助け出して
I'm about to drown, so please come save me
君に Falling 恋の SOS ずっと胸が苦しいんです
Falling for you, a love SOS, my chest has been aching for so long
早く Rescue 恋のテレパシー 早く気付いて
Rescue me quickly, love telepathy, please notice soon
これは Falling 恋の SOS もっと君に近づきたい
This is falling, a love SOS, I want to get closer to you
終わらせて 片想い My heart 全部抱きしめて
End this unrequited love, hold my whole heart tight
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our fresh heart-throbs resound
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
With the best time and the best friends
煌めきを放て！
Emit that sparkle!
キラメキライダー☆
Kirameki Rider☆
覚えてるかな 最初の歌
I wonder if you remember our first song
私 声が震えていた
My voice was trembling back then
あの日から続く未来は
The future continuing from that day
みんなと掴んだ奇跡だよ
Is a miracle we grabbed together
もっともっともっともっと加速するハート
A heart accelerating more and more
行くよどこまでも 準備はOK?
We'll go anywhere, are you ready?
開け 夢の扉を いざ行こう！
Open the door to dreams, let's go now!
夢見る空へ
Toward the sky of dreams
差し出された手はギュッと離さずに
Don't let go of the hand held out to you
ひとりじゃない 描き出すトキメキ
You're not alone, the excitement starts to unfold
振り向くことなく まっすぐに
Straight ahead, without looking back
行くよ 夢見る空へ
Let's go, toward the sky of dreams
笑い合ったことや 尽きそうにない話
The times we laughed together, and the endless stories
思い出いっぱいなのに あっという間な日々
Even with so many memories, the days went by in a flash
上書きじゃなくて
Not as an overwrite
名前一度でハートん
With just your name, my heart—
どれも全部大事にしてあげる
I'll treasure every single one of them
わんっはー！みんなのためが力になる
One-ha! Doing it for everyone gives me strength
あるっはー！今日も賑やかすぎるくらい
Al-ha! Today is almost too lively again
笑顔がもう止まらない
I can't stop smiling anymore
想いは膨らんでいく
These feelings keep growing bigger
重ねて今ギュッと噛み締めた
Tightly reflecting on the moments we've shared
一人時間（とき）を数えては広がる
Counting the moments as they spread out
風を感じたら真っ直ぐに
Once I feel the breeze, I'll go straight ahead
いくよ、夢見る空へ
Here I go, towards the sky of my dreams
背伸びしては手を伸ばす
Standing on my toes and reaching out my hand
憧れの…
To the place I admire...
行き先示す星になろう
I'll become a star that shows the way
続くその旅に手を差し伸べ合えたら
If we can reach out to each other on this journey
すぐに届くはずさ
We'll surely reach it soon
そっと踏み出した小さな勇気がもう
The small bit of courage I took a step with
消えないように繋げよう
Let's connect it so it never fades
不安も愛しさも大切に抱きしめて
Cherishing and embracing both anxiety and love
共に行くよ 目を合わせて
We'll go together, eye to eye
3 2 1!
Three, two, one!
晴れ渡る空へ
To the clear blue sky
飛び出せるよ
I can leap out now
突き抜けてゆく
Breaking through everything
僕たちの透き通る決意 今
Our transparent determination, right now
まだまだ止められないよ
I still can't be stopped
ありふれた今日こそ ときめきに変えて
Turning even an ordinary today into excitement
もっと僕たちがいつまでも
Because we will always
背中を押すから
Keep pushing you forward
憧れの舞台立ちたい
I want to stand on the stage I admire
らしく輝きたい
I want to shine in my own way
時に涙して また笑いあいたい
Crying sometimes, but wanting to laugh together again
同じ未来をみたい
I want to see the same future
あの夢手にしたい
I want to grasp that dream
踏み出そう、奇跡の一歩を！
Let's take a step, a miraculous step forward!
息切らして 夢追いかけたい
Running out of breath, I want to chase my dreams
ワクワク止まらない
This excitement won't stop
ゾワゾワ超えていく 世界に見せてあげる
Going beyond the chills, I'll show the whole world
アクセスしてみたい
I want to reach out and connect
後悔なんてここにない
There's no room for regrets here
それぞれ違った心で
With our each unique hearts
スパークルは！
Sparkle on!
はい、ということで…
Alright, so...
ホロライブいにご…ホロライブメドレーでした！
That was the Hololive Inigo... Hololive Medley!
自分の事務所なのに…ｗ
Even though it's my own agency... (laughs)
え、どうだった？なんか激エモだったんじゃないですか？
So, how was it? It was super emotional, right?
そしてね、この衣装は初めてもらったアイドル衣装なんですよね。
And you know, this outfit is actually the very first idol costume I ever received.
なんかあの時を思い出してなんかすごいジーンときてしまいますわね。
Remembering those times really makes me feel quite moved.
そう、まつりはね、元々そのアイドルデビューじゃなかったんですよ、ホロライブって。
Right, because originally, Matsuri didn't debut as an 'idol' back then in Hololive.
で、この衣装もらって、「よし、アイドルとして頑張るぞ！」というね、
But when I got this outfit, it made me think, "Alright, I'm gonna do my best as an idol!"
気持ちを改めて思い出し、頑張っていこうかなという気持ちでございます。
Remembering that feeling makes me want to keep working hard going forward.
はい、そしてそして、今回も！
Okay, and next up, just like always!
誕生日グッズでございまーす！やったー！
It's time for the birthday merchandise! Yay!
嬉しい！ということで、一つずつ紹介していきます。
I'm so happy! So, let me introduce them one by one.
まずはこちら、ドドン！
First up is this, ta-da!
「薄すぎ！」おっぱいマウスパッド！やったー！
The "Way Too Thin!" Oppai Mouse Pad! Yay!
イラストはえく先生。まつり待望のね、マウスパッドでございますよ。
The illustration is by Eku-sensei. It's the mouse pad Matsuri has been waiting for.
もう、あのちなみに言うと、膨らみはないですｗ
By the way, just so you know, there is no 'padding' at all. (laughs)
普通のマウスパッドとなっております。
It's just a completely flat mouse pad.
【薄すぎ！おっぱいマウスパッド】
[Too Thin! Boob Mouse Pad]
ねえ。こうやってあの癒やすことはちょっと難しいんですが、
Hey. It's a bit difficult to heal you in this way, but...
もうちょっとガチ照れな「きゅん」みたいな感じなのでね、
it's more like a real, blushing 'ba-dump' feeling,
あのもう心から癒やされていくという感じで。はい。どうですか？
so it's like you'll be healed from the bottom of your heart. Yes. What do you think?
素晴らしいことでございましょう。そして続いてこちら！
Isn't it wonderful? And next up is this!
じゃーん！ランダムアクリルキーホルダー！
Ta-dah! Random Acrylic Keychains!
ランダムアクリルキーホルダー
Random Acrylic Keychain
なんと夏色まつり先生のね、描き下ろしでございますよ！
Believe it or not, these were drawn by Natsuiro Matsuri-sensei!
ランダムアクリルキーホルダー。もうまつりがグッズのイラスト描くって、
Random Acrylic Keychains. Matsuri drawing the merch illustrations herself...
なかなか無いでございますから、すごい愛情込めて描きました。
...is quite rare, so I put a lot of love into drawing them.
もうチュチュチュッてしながら描いたので、
I was like 'chu-chu-chu' while drawing them,
ぜひね全種類コンプリートしてみてください。そして続いてこちら！
so please try to complete the whole set. And next is this!
まつりちゃんのぬいぐるみ サブカルジャージ衣装バージョンでございます！
Matsuri-chan's plushie, Subculture Jersey Outfit version!
まつりぬいぐるみ サブカルジャージ衣装ver.
Matsuri Plushie Subculture Jersey Outfit ver.
キービジュのイラストと同じサブカルジャージの衣装の、なんとぬい、が登場しちゃいますよ。
The plushie of the subculture jersey outfit from the key visual is finally here.
キービジュのように押し倒すことはちょっと現実だと叶わないけど、
Pinning me down like in the key visual isn't possible in reality, but...
ぬいなら、ぬいならできちゃうということで、
with the plushie, with the plushie you can do it!
ぜひたくさん可愛がって色んなところに連れて行ってあげてください。さらにこちら！
So please cherish it and take it with you everywhere. Furthermore, this!
まつりすマグカップ！
Matsurisu Mug Cup!
まつりすマグカップ
Matsurisu Mug Cup
みんなにはマグカップになってもらいました。どんな罪を犯してこんな姿になっちまったんだ、
I've turned all of you into mug cups. I wonder what sins you committed to end up like this...
って感じでございますが。あはははは！
...is how it feels. Hahaha!
ま、自分なのでね、あの「これが俺の姿か」と思いながら使っていただけたらなと思います。
Well, since it's 'you', I hope you use it while thinking, 'So this is what I look like.'
まつりちゃんも使わせていただきます。最後に、ボイス！じゃじゃーん！
I'll be using it too. Lastly, the voice pack! Ta-dah!
シチュエーションボイス「逆襲のまつりす」。
Situation Voice: 'Matsurisu's Counterattack'.
なんだ、「逆襲のまつりす」ってなんだ？はい。今回ねキービジュのシチュエーションに至るまでのストーリーが、
Wait, what's 'Matsurisu's Counterattack'? Well, the story leading up to the key visual situation...
ここに詰まっちゃってますので、どんなシチュエーションなのかちょっと気になる方は、
...is packed into this, so if you're curious about the situation,
ぜひゲットしてみてください。そして、フルセットを購入いただいた方全員に！
please go get it. And, for everyone who purchases the Full Set!
直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードがついてきちゃいます！
You'll get a postcard with a handwritten signature and a foil-stamped replica message!
フルセット購入特典：直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカード
Full Set Purchase Bonus: Postcard with handwritten signature and foil-stamped replica message
えっとちょっとね、来年は直筆やるかちょっとまだ未定でございますので、
Umm, I haven't decided if I'll do handwritten signatures next year,
ぜひ、ぜひぜひぜひぜひ、全員に書かせていただきますので。初めてなんですよ、それも。
so please, definitely get it since I'll be signing every single one. It's a first for me, too.
全員にサイン書くの初めてだから、ぜひ手に入れてください。来年やるかわかんないからね。
It's the first time I'm signing for everyone, so please get it. I don't know if I'll do it next year.
さらにですね、タレントプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として、
Also, as a full set bonus for the Talent Premium Goods,
2024年9月から発売された「hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME」で使用できるカードが1枚ついてきちゃいますよ！
you'll get one card that can be used in the 'hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME' released in Sept 2024!
まつりはね前回のグッズでちょっと特典に付いてなかったので、今回付いてくるよって感じになっております。
Matsuri wasn't included as a bonus in the last merch, but this time I am.
hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME PRカード HBD24-067「夏色まつり」
hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME PR Card HBD24-067 'Natsuiro Matsuri'
えっと、同封する、同封であってるよね日本語。はい。ホロライブプロダクション公式ショップで購入されたお客様のみの、
Umm, 'enclosed'... that's the right Japanese, right? Yes. Only for customers who purchase at the Hololive Production Official Shop...
お客様のみの対象となっておりますので、よろしくお願いします。
...will be eligible, so thank you for your understanding.
特典につくのはゲームで1枚だけ使用でき、推しをアピールできるキーカード、
The bonus is a key card you can use once in a game to show off your 'oshi',
「推しホロメンカード」でございます！そしてそしてそして、さらにでございますよ！
the 'Oshi Holomen Card'! And, and, and, there's even more!
まだある！アルバム！！デデデデデデデ！
There's still more! An album!! Dun-dun-dun-dun-dun!
なんとまつりちゃん、ファーストアルバム「Chasing the Dream スポットライトは放課後に」が、
Matsuri-chan's first album, 'Chasing the Dream: The Spotlight is After School',
なんと本日！11月1日受注開始でございます！パンパカパーン！
is available for pre-order starting today, November 1st! Ta-da-da-dah!
Natsuiro Matsuri 1st Album "Chasing the Dream スポットライトは放課後に"
Natsuiro Matsuri 1st Album "Chasing the Dream: The Spotlight is After School"
まつりちゃん初のオリジナル楽曲「君と眺める夏の花」をはじめ、これまで配信リリースしてきた作品のほか、
Starting with my first original song 'Summer Flowers with You', and other works released so far,
JINさんはじめ豪華作曲陣が書き下ろしてくださった新曲も収録しちゃってますよ！
it also includes new songs written by a luxurious lineup of composers, including Jin-san!
計14曲の超ボリュームなアルバムになっているので、ぜひ手に入れちゃってください。
It's a super voluminous album with 14 songs in total, so please get your hands on it.
コンセプトはね、アイドルのまつりちゃんと、普段の女子高生のまつりちゃんのこう両面みたいな、
The concept is like the two sides of me: Idol Matsuri and the everyday high schooler Matsuri.
両方が楽しめるようなねアルバムになってます。
It's an album where you can enjoy both sides.
形態は2つありまして、完全生産限定盤と、通常盤をご用意しております。
There are two editions available: the Limited First Press Edition and the Standard Edition.
完全生産限定盤 / 通常盤
Limited First Press Edition / Standard Edition
完全生産限定盤はですね、セパレートタイプのオリジナルカレンダーがついてきちゃいますよ！
The Limited First Press Edition comes with a separate-type original calendar!
そして両形態に封入特典として、まつりちゃんからの複製お手紙が入っています。
And as an enclosed bonus for both editions, there's a replica letter from me.
ただし、数量限定のランダムでですね、複製お手紙の代わりに、
However, in limited quantities at random, instead of the replica letter...
直筆お手紙がもらえちゃう案内が封入されていますので、ぜひぜひゲットしちゃってください！
...a notice stating you'll receive a handwritten letter is enclosed, so please go get it!
数量限定ランダムで「直筆お手紙」当選案内が封入されます。
A winning notice for a 'Handwritten Letter' will be enclosed at random in limited quantities.
以上、アルバム情報でした！
That's all for the album information!
（拍手）
(Applause)
そしてなんと
And what's more,
アルバムに収録する新曲のうち一曲をですね
one of the new songs included in the album...
本日このあと披露しちゃいまーす！
...will be performed today right after this!
タイトルは
The title is...
ウーニャカ ニャンニャン！
Un-nyaka Nyan-nyan!
楽曲はですね、かいりきベアさんに楽曲いただきました
The song was provided by Kairiki Bear.
めちゃめちゃ可愛い！
It's super cute!
MVもですね、このあとプレミア公開ありますので
The MV will also have a premiere after this.
0時からあの楽曲リリースもありますので
The song will also be released at midnight.
あのぜひよろしくお願いしますね
So please check it out.
プ...プレミア公開も一緒に見ようね。はい。
Let's watch the premiere together. Yes.
じゃあちょっと着替えてきますので
Well, I'm going to change my outfit.
ちょっとここで待ってて。ワクワクって言いながらね。
Wait here for a bit. Say "Waku-waku" [excited].
あのゲストパートと同じようにワクワクって言いながら待っててください。
Wait like you did during the guest part, saying "Waku-waku".
じゃあ行ってきまーす！
Well, I'm off!
ワクワク！ワクワク！
Waku-waku! Waku-waku!
真夜中にトケタ
Melted in the middle of the night
感情は爪立てて
Emotions dig in their claws
(真夜中にトケタ 感情は爪立てて)
(Melted in the middle of the night, emotions dig in their claws)
檻から見慣れた
Familiar from the cage
世界は牙向いて
The world bares its fangs
(檻から見慣れた 世界は牙向いて)
(Familiar from the cage, the world bares its fangs)
真夜中見かねた
Unable to watch the middle of the night
感情は飢えた目で
Emotions with hungry eyes
(真夜中見かねた 感情は飢えた目で)
(Unable to watch the middle of the night, emotions with hungry eyes)
軽やかに逃げた
Lightly escaped
優しさ求めて
Seeking kindness
(軽やかに逃げた 優しさ求めて)
(Lightly escaped, seeking kindness)
愛されたい の想い
The desire to be loved
愛されないの Give me
I'm not loved, give me
愛してるも重い？
Is "I love you" also heavy?
愛さえないの？もういい？
Is there no love? Is it enough?
愛情結晶頂戴
Give me the crystal of affection
あなたを見てるのニャ
I'm watching you, nya
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン
Nyan-nyaka Rin-rin-rin
おねだり
Begging
さあ手懐けてよ もっと めいっぱい
Come on, tame me more, with all your heart
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン
Nyan-nyaka Rin-rin-rin
おでかけ？
Going out?
しがみついて 何処も行かせない！
Clinging to you, I won't let you go anywhere!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
Un-nyaka Nyan-nyan Un-nyan-nyan
甘いキャンディ頂戴な
Give me some sweet candy
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
Un-nyaka Nyan-nyan Un-nyan-nyan
ハッピーライフ頂戴な
Give me a happy life
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
Un-nyaka Nyan-nyan Un-nyan-nyan
叱らないで頂戴な
Please don't scold me
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
Un-nyaka Nyan-nyan Un-nyan-nyan
ほんとの「好き」頂戴な
Give me your true "love"
縄張り土足で
In my territory with shoes on
感情日丸出しで
Emotions laid bare
(縄張り土足で 感情日丸出しで)
(In my territory with shoes on, emotions laid bare)
幸せになれた
I was able to be happy
未来が牙向いて
The future bares its fangs
(幸せになれた 未来が牙向いて)
(I was able to be happy, the future bares its fangs)
突き放さないでいて
Don't push me away
切り捨てず傍で
Don't cast me aside, stay by my side
お傍で お傍で
By my side, by my side
お傍で見ているのニャ
I'm watching you from by your side, nya
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン
Nyan-nyaka Rin-rin-rin
おねがい
Please
さあ頭撫でて もっと ぜーいっぱい
Come on, stroke my head more, with all your might
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン
Nyan-nyaka Rin-rin-rin
おあずけ？
On hold?
甘えて泣いて 此処に居させて！
Spoil me, cry, let me stay here!
ニャンニャカ言ったって 伝わんない？
Even if I say "nyan-nyaka", it doesn't get through?
どーしたって こーしたって 寂しいの
No matter what I do, I'm lonely
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン
Nyan-nyaka Rin-rin-rin
おもいっきり
With all my heart
あざとい声 わざと聞かせる
Letting you hear my coy voice on purpose
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン
Nyan-nyaka Rin-rin-rin
おねだり
Begging
さあ手懐けてよ もっと めいっぱい
Come on, tame me more, with all your heart
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン
Nyan-nyaka Rin-rin-rin
おやすみ？
Good night?
しがみついて 今夜寝かせない！
Clinging to you, I won't let you sleep tonight!
ウーニャカ ニニャニャ ウーニャンニャン
Un-nyaka Nyan-nyan Un-nyan-nyan
甘いキャンディ頂戴な
Give me some sweet candy
ウーニャカ ニニャニャ ウーニャンニャン
Un-nyaka Nyan-nyan Un-nyan-nyan
ハッピーライフ頂戴な
Give me a happy life
ウーニャカ ニニャニャ ウーニャンニャン
Un-nyaka Nyan-nyan Un-nyan-nyan
抱きしめて頂戴な
Please hold me
ウーニャカ ニニャニャ ウーニャンニャン
Un-nyaka Nyan-nyan Un-nyan-nyan
ほんとの「好き」頂戴な
Give me your true "love"